孩子们 这里的花更多 过来摘吧
There's some more flowers, kids.
Go pick 'em.
哦……
Yeah!
这朵真漂亮！
That's a pretty one!
-我一朵花都没有
-那就去找一朵吧 那边就有
- I don't have one.
- Well, go look for one, over there.
哦 这朵真漂亮  让我看看
Oh, that's beautiful. Let me look at that.
让我看看
Let me look at that!
你们可以把花带回家给爸爸妈妈 多香啊！
Now you can take them home
to your parents. Don't they smell nice!
你好
Hi.
怎么不把地上的信捡起来 杰弗里？
Too much trouble to pick the mail up
off the floor, Geoffrey?
没听到吗？
Hello?
来看看这朵花
Look at this flower.
别这样！阿塔韦！
All right! Attaway!
知道吗 我想我找到稀罕物了
You know, I think I actually
found something rare.
什么？
What?
这朵花 我想是grex（可能是一种植物）
什么？
- This plant. I think it's a grex.
- A what?
G-R-E-X 是两个不同物种交叉授粉
G-R-E-X. That's when
two species cross-pollinate
产生的第三种独特的物种
and produce a third
completely unique one.
听听注释：
And listen to this:
Epilobic 来源于希腊语的epi
在……之上 或者 是指一种豆荚类植物
"Epilobic, from the Greek epi: upon,
and lobos: a pod."
很多品种都是危险的野草 避免接触
"Many of the species are dangerous
weeds and should be avoided."
危险？
Dangerous?
对于花园来说
In the garden.
看到没？ 这么快就扎根了
See? Look how quickly it roots.
他们在欧洲很多饱经战火的城市
"Their rapid and widespread growth
was even observed
快速的生长和广泛的分布已经引起注意
in many of the war-torn cities of Europe."
确实 这类植物中的一些在被破坏的地表生长的很好
"lndeed, some of these plants
may thrive on devastated ground."
我们周末出去维尔怎么样？周五就上飞机 嗯？
Why don't we go up to Vail
for the weekend? Fly up Friday, hm?
好吧 也许……没问题
OK, maybe. Sure.
杰弗里！我正看书呢！
Geoffrey! I'm trying to read!
你心情不错嘛
You're in a good mood.
我等着看晚上的季后赛呢
Well, I got something
to look forward to tonight - playoffs.
杰弗里！
Geoffrey.
-怎么啦？
-我正看书呢
- What?
- I'm reading.
好吧！我会戴上耳机的 好了 满意了吧？
OK! I'll put the earphones on.
There, see? Happy?
算了 我去楼下看书
Never mind. I'll go downstairs.
开门 Qui est l?
谁？
Comment? Qui est l?
Who is it?
卫生署
Department of Health.
晚安 贝纳尔先生 见到你真高兴
Bonsoir, Monsieur Bennell.
How nice to see you.
那是什么东西？
What is that supposed to be?
这是塞尔韦勒炖鱼
It is cervelles en matelote.
说英语 这东西是什么做的？
In English, what would I be eating
if I ate that?
哦 是把小牛的脑子放在红酒里煮
除了红酒还有什么？
- Ah. Calves' brains in red wine.
- Red wine and what else?
玉米 这可不能说 这是秘密 贝纳尔先生
Mais, c'est impossible. It's impossible.
It's a secret, Mr Bennell.
卫生署可不管什么秘密不秘密的 亨利
You don't have any secrets
from the Department of Health, Henri.
要用勃艮第葡萄酒 牛高汤
A good young Burgundy, brown stock,
百里香 欧芹-一小支
thyme, parsley - just a sprig.
刺山柑 新鲜的月桂叶和大蒜
Capers,... a fresh bay leaf, and garlic.
就这些？
是 是的
- That's all?
- Oui. Yes.
这是什么？
刺山柑
- What is that?
- A caper.
不对
No.
那你说这是什么呢？
Do you presume to tell us
what is in this stock?
这是老鼠屎
什么
- It's a rat turd.
- A what?
老鼠屎
A rat turd.
刺山柑！
老鼠屎！
- A caper!
- A rat turd.
刺山柑！
A caper!
如果这是刺山柑
If it's a caper,
吃吃看
eat it.
我要吊销你的执照 亨利
I'm gonna bring you up
for permit revocation, Henri.
你做的这些烂东西可值不了这么多钱
You're charging way too much
to be serving crap like that in here.
但是 先生 这是意外 你知道我们有多小心的
But, Monsieur, it is an accident.
You know how careful we are.
你好？
Hello?
是伊莉莎白吗？
是的
- Elizabeth?
- Yes.
我吵醒你了吗？
不 你好马修
- Wake you up?
- No. Hi, Matthew.
他们把我的车窗打碎了
哦 不！
- They busted the window of my car.
- Oh, no!
用一瓶就砸的-连好酒都舍不得用
Threw a bottle of wine at it -
not even good wine.
勇士队赢了 我想你们全家都很高兴吧
The Warriors won,
so I guess your household's happy.
当然了
Yes.
你在干什么？
哦 什么都没干
- What are you doing?
- Oh, nothing.
如果你现在就去睡觉 那你就能早点起
If you go to sleep now,
you can get up early.
哦 马修…
Oh, Matthew...
如果你能在七点半来 那你8点前就能开始测试了
If you can come in at 7.30,
you can run the tests before 8 o'clock.
别说了！马修…别说了 我早晨八点前到不了
Stop! Matthew... stop. I'm not coming in
before 8 o'clock in the morning!
我必须要给减税听证会点压力
- I gotta force the abatement hearing.
-他们只在星期三才有免费名额
-不行 马修！
- Wednesday's their only free slot.
- No, Matthew!
我八点前肯定到不了！
I will not be there before eight!
你知道我提名你做年度明星公务员吗？
I nominated you for
Civil Servant of the Year award.
真的 我想你能通过
It's true. I think you'll win.
好好好 我七点半一定到
我会帮你做沙门氏菌测试的
OK, OK, OK. I'll be in at 7.30.
I'll run a salmonella test for you.
谢谢 明早见
Thank you. See you in the morning.
晚安 明天见
Good night. I'll see you in the morning.
再见
- Bye.
杰弗里 天啊！你起床多久了？
Geoffrey, my God!
How long have you been up?
没多久
Not long.
你在干什么呢？
What are you doing?
杰弗里？
Geoffrey?
我要罚死他们（法国餐馆）
这些扇贝是拿切碎的鳐鱼片冒充的
I wanna throw the book at him. Those
scallops are just cut-up pieces of skate.
抱歉 我这就开始测试
I'm sorry. I can start the tests right away.
没什么 这些土豆好像有点不对劲
It's OK...And something's wrong with the potato.
酸奶油也是假的 还有这些韭黄
Either the sour cream is phoney,
or the chives.
对不起 我没有睡过头 都怪杰弗里
I'm sorry. I got up on time.
It was Geoffrey.
这次那个疯牙医有怎么了？
我不知道 他就是很怪
- What did the mad dentist do this time?
- I don't know. He was just weird.
他是疯子 牙医都是疯子
He's crazy. All dentists are crazy.
你晚了吗？
没有
- Are you late?
- No.
他并不是平时的那种古怪
He was weird not the way he usually is.
那肯定是好现象
That can only be an improvement.
这个 不是 这让我很紧张
Well, it's not. It's got me really nervous.
告诉他如果不理发就滚出去
Tell him to shape up or get out.
这是他的家
让他自己选
- It's his house.
- Make him an offer.
你看到这个一定会高兴的
是什么？
- Here's something that'll cheer you up.
- What?
这么近还看不见吗？
Ever seen one of these up close?
这是什么？
你看像什么？
- What is it?
- What does it look like?
刺山柑吗？
是刺山柑吗？
- A caper?
到底是什么？
What is it?
是老鼠屎 但是这汤汁味道还不坏
我帮你捉了只老鼠
- A rat turd, but the sauce was delicious.
- I got you a rat.
你抓到了吗？
我真抓住了 是个大家伙
- Did you find one?
- I've got it. It was a biggie.
这样我们就可以公布他的卫生不良问题了
OK, we'll get a declaration
of "unsanitary" on him.
我们一会再谈好吗？
好的
- I'll talk to you later, OK?
- OK.
还有什么我能效劳的？
没有了 别担心 去吧
- What can I do?
- Nothing. Don't worry. Go on.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
哦 对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
嗨 说吧 告诉我今天要干些什么
我知道今天的计划
- Hey, come on. Tell me what I've done.
- I understand today's plan.
事出突然 伊莉莎白 我还得再出去一趟
Something's come up, Elizabeth.
I have to go back out again.
现在吗？我们不去看比赛吗？
Now? Weren't we going to the game?
我把票都给了一位病人
The Warriors.
I gave the tickets to a patient.
你今晚不去看比赛了吗？
You're not gonna see tonight's game?
没办法
No choice.
杰弗里 你到底怎么了？
Geoffrey, what is the matter with you?
我没事 只是要去开会
I'm fine. I just have to go to a meeting.
开会？开哪门子会？
Meeting? What kind of a meeting?
伊莉莎白 我想我不需要什么事都跟你汇报吧
Elizabeth, I don't think
I have to justify my every move to you.
杰弗里 这可不像你的风格
Geoffrey, this isn't like you.
别这样 我只是关心你而已
Please, come on. I just want it to be nice...
伊莉莎白 你是怎么回事？
Elizabeth, what's the matter with you?
没什么
Nothing.
请进！
Come in!
嗨
Hi.
还好吗？
How you doing?
疯子是不会感觉到自己发疯的 是吗？
Is it true that if you think
you're losing your mind, you're not?
我希望是这样
Well, I hope so.
我知道这听起来有点荒唐
I know this is gonna sound insane.
什么？
What?
杰弗里不是杰弗里
Geoffrey is not Geoffrey.
你怎么知道？
我就是知道
- How do you know?
- I know.
表面上看 杰弗里还是杰弗里
On the outside Geoffrey is still Geoffrey,
但是 我能感觉到他跟原来不一样了
but on the inside
I can tell there is something different.
有些东西消失了
Something is missing.
是什么？
没有七情六欲
- What?
- Emotion, feelings.
他已经不是原来的他了
He's just not the same person.
真的 你知道我的意思吗？我知道这听着有点疯狂
Really, you know what I mean?
I know it sounds crazy.
是的 我知道你的意思 我想我知道 吃饭没？
Yeah. I know what you mean, I think.
Have you eaten?
我不饿
吃点芹菜吧
- I'm not hungry.
- Have some celery.
我不…
张嘴 张嘴 张嘴
- I'm not...
- Eat, eat, eat.
我们可以在外面吃 今天月色不错
We can eat outside. It's a beautiful night.
拿着那块肉 好吗？ 切一下
Take that meat there, will you?
Chop it up.
还有把姜递给我 就在那儿 已经切好的那些
And hand me the ginger,
the stuff that's chopped up there.
还有呢 这真的很怪
You wanna know something else?
This is really weird.
我去过他姐姐诺拉那儿 我想跟她说这些事
I went to see his sister Nora to talk to her about it.
但是我开不了口 我忍住了
But I couldn't. I stopped myself.
她也变了吗？
She changed, too?
你觉得我疯了吗？
怎么会
- Do you think I'm crazy?
- No.
你想去看看我的老伙计戴维金博纳
D'you wanna go see my friend David Kibner?
那个精神病学家吗？
不是看病
- The psychiatrist?
- Not like that.
跟他说说 他会给你指点迷津的
Talk to him. He would put things into perspective.
我没疯
不不不 我是认真的
- I'm not crazy.
- No, no, no. I'm serious.
他会结束这一切 不管杰弗里是在外偷情还是玩断臂
He would eliminate whether Geoffrey
was having an affair, or had become gay.
或者是他染上性病 即使他加入了共和党
Whether he had a social disease,or had become a Republican.
任何让你感到他不同以往的事
All the things that could have happened
to have made you feel he had changed.
知道我的意思吗？要不要去见见他？
D'you know what I mean?
You wanna go see him?
你把我当疯子
You think I'm nuts.
不 没有 你的眼睛还会那样转吗？
No, I don't.
Can you still do the thing with your eyes?
如果你没疯 那你就转给我看
If you're not crazy,
you can do that thing with your eyes.
你没疯
You're not crazy.
真好吃
This is delicious.
你厨艺不错
You're a great cook.
杰弗里什么时候回来？
What time is Geoffrey getting back?
他说不用等他了
He said not to wait up for him.
你还想再来点酒吗？
D'you want some more wine?
早安！
你好
- Morning!
- Hello.
一件 二件 藤太太 这个上面有一块咖啡渍
One, two... Mrs Teng,
this one's got a coffee stain on it.
这里
Here.
那不是咖啡
这是咖啡 我自己弄上去的
- That's not coffee.
- That is coffee. I put it there myself.
可能洗不掉了
Maybe not come out.
你是医生 对吗？
You doctor, right?
我？不是 我是卫生署的公务员
Me? No. Health Department. Civil servant.
你要看医生吗？
Do you need a doctor?
我老婆…病了
My wife... sick.
她怎么了？
她不对
- What's wrong with her?
- She wrong.
她不对劲吗？
她不是我老婆了
- She's not right?
- That not my wife.
你是说她……？
You mean, she's...?
不 不 不一样了
No, no. Different.
她不再是我老婆
That not my wife!
最近怎么样？哈利？
How you doin', Harry?
嗨 小家伙 最近怎么样？
Hey, pooch. How you doin', boy?
你去哪了？我都急疯了 到处都找不到你
Where you been? You've been driving me
crazy. I've been looking all over for you.
怎么了？
What's the matter with you?
没事吗？
You all right?
说话呀 伊丽莎白
Talk to me, Elizabeth.
这些人到处都是
I keep seeing these people
他们互相都认识
all recognising each other.
他们在互相传着些什么
Something was passing between them all.
秘密
Some secret.
这是一个阴谋 我知道
It's a conspiracy. I know it.
哪有什么阴谋
There can't be a conspiracy.
马修 告诉你 这里正在发生着什么事
Matthew, I'm telling you, something's going on here.
一些让我害怕的事
Something that scares me.
我今天想去看杰弗里 想跟他谈谈
I tried to see Geoffrey today,
to talk to him.
他一上午都在自己的办公室里
He's always in his office in the morning.
这真的很怪
It really was weird.
杰弗里跟各种奇怪的人会面
Geoffrey was meeting all sorts of strange people.
互相间传递着什么
Things were being passed between them.
这些人你全都不认识吗？
我都不认识
- None were people you knew?
- I didn't know any of them.
说不定他们都是杰弗里的病人呢
Maybe they were patients of Geoffrey's.
哦 不 不 马修 我知道他们不是病人
Oh, no, no, Matthew. I know they weren't.
我跟着他从镇子的这边跟到那边
I followed him from one end of town to the other,
他走到哪里都要跟这种怪人碰面
and everywhere he went he had these meetings with strange people.
我感觉这样跟踪监视他傻透了
I felt so stupid sneaking around spying on him,
但是我不能跟他说上话 我又能干什么呢？
but I can't talk to him. What can I do?
好吧 金博纳应该能够解释一些事
OK. Well, Kibner will be able
to explain something.
我不需要精神病学家
I don't need a psychiatrist.
忘掉他是精神病学家
Just forget that he's a psychiatrist.
把他当作一个智者 这才是他
Just think of him as an intelligent man, which is what he is.
只是一个读书会 他是名人 非常有名
It's a book party. He's a celebrity.He's very famous.
只要你能忘掉他是精神病学家 你一定会喜欢他的
And you will like him,if you forget that he's a psychiatrist.
我不知道 我不知道
I don't know... I don't know.
马修 我一直住在这里
Matthew, I've lived in this city all my life,
但是今天不知怎么的 我感觉所有东西都不对劲
but somehow today I felt everything had changed.
人都不一样了 不光是杰弗里 是所有人
People were different. Notjust Geoffrey, but everybody.
昨天一切看着都还没挺好的
Yesterday it all seemed normal.
今天虽然表面上看没什么变化 但是实际并不是这样的
Today everything seemed the same, but it wasn't.
这简直是个噩梦
It was a nightmare.
让人直冒冷汗
It really became frightening.
就好象一夜之间整个城都变了
It was like the whole city had changed overnight.
我跟你说过一个英国骆驼军团的故事吗?说过吗?
Did I ever tell you the one
about the English Camel Corps? Did l?
他们困在沙漠里 在撒哈拉
They're trapped in the desert,
in the Sahara desert.
他们被隆美尔包围了40天 吃的没有了
They've been surrounded by Rommel
for 40 days and they've run out of food.
然后统帅赶来对他们做了一个演说
And the captain comes and makes an announcement to the men.
他说
He says,
伙计们 我有一个好消息和一个坏消息
"Men, I have some good news and some bad news for you."
一个人说
等等 你跟我说过这个故事
- One of the men says...
- Wait. You have told me this.
我能再说一遍吗?
Can I tell it to you again?
小心!
Look out!
哦 天啊!锁上门!
Oh, my God! Lock the door!
他们来了!
我们该帮帮他
- They're coming!
- We should help.
救命!救命! 他们来了 他们来了 听啊!
Help! Help! They're coming. They're coming. Listen!
他都吓出屎来了
他真让人害怕
- He's smashed out of his skull.
- He's terrified.
下一个就是你 求求你!求求你!你就是下一个 我们危在旦夕
You're next. Please! Please!You're next. We're in danger!
听我说... 发生了很可怕的事
Listen to me... Something terrible!
求你了 下一个就是你 他们就在这里 他们已经来了!
Please. You're next!Here they are. They're already here!
救命!下一个就是你!
Help! You're next!
他们来了 他们来了
他一定是做了什么
- They're coming. They're coming...
- He must have done something.
警察会帮他的
The policeman'll help.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
可怜的人 他刚才说的什么意思？
That poor man.What was he talking about?
到了书店我就打电话把我看到的一切告诉警察
I'll phone a witness report in from the bookstore.
马修 你在这儿太好了!这些人都快把我折磨疯了!
Matthew, thank God you're here! These people are driving me nuts.
我们一起吃晚饭吗?
不 我不能
- Are we gonna have dinner?
- No, I can't.
这儿有电话吗?
在角落里
- Is there a phone?
- Around the corner.
这是伊丽莎白・德里斯科尔 这是杰克・伯利克
这就是那个伊丽莎白吗？
- Elizabeth Driscoll, Jack Bellicec.
- This is the Elizabeth?
这书太烂了 金博纳的书太烂了
The book is awful. Kibner's book is awful.
他的构思一文不值 一文不值
His ideas are garbage. Pure garbage.
你怎么能这么说一个像金博纳这样的人呢？
How can you say that about a man like Kibner?
我不是说像金博纳的人 我就是在说金博纳
Not a man like Kibner. I'm saying it about Kibner.
他每半年就赶出一部书来 我要用半年才能写出一行了
He dashes a book off every six months.
Takes me six months to write one line.
为什么？
因为我字斟句酌
- Why?
- Cos I pick each word individually.
这有什么可炫的？
我又没有跟你说话 不是吗？
- What's so hot about that?
- I wasn't even talking to you, was l?
在莱文沃思街和…
On the corner of Leavenworth and...
特克街
特克街吗？特克街交汇出
- Turk.
- Turk? Turk.
那是他吗？
Is that him?
是的
Yes.
是的！
Yes!
哪有什么好炫的？有什么好炫的？ 我不知道…
"What's so hot about that?
What's so hot about that?" I don't know...
你们应该有记录的 因为那里有一位骑摩托的警官在现场
You must have a report on it
cos there was a motorcycle officer there
还有一辆救护车赶过去
他们跟不上我的思维
- and an ambulance on the way.
- They follow me.
他们不理解我
你不用向他们证明什么
- They don't understand me.
- You don't have to prove yourself to them.
你说的轻巧
当然 我亲眼所见
- That's easy for you to say.
- Of course I saw it.
那个人顺着马路跑
这是浪漫和伤感的
- The man was running down the street.
- It's romantic, sentimental,
他趴在我的车上
后工业化的胡扯
- He landed on my car.
- post-industrial nonsense.
等一下 我正在跟警察通话呢
Just a second. I'm talking to the police.
不 他的血流了一地
有什么麻烦吗？
- No, he was bleeding on the road.
- What seems to be the trouble?
在吗？是的
Hello? Yeah.
别把名字告诉警察
Don't ever give your name to cops.
莱文沃思街跟塔克街路口 我等着
Leavenworth and Turk. I'll hold.
但是他不是我的丈夫了
But he isn't my husband!
他只是看着像而已 他是冒充的！
It's someone who looks like him.He's an impostor!
好了 凯瑟琳 他就是你丈夫 你我都认识他
Now, Katherine, he's your husband.You know him and I know him.
直到今天我才发现 因为他脖子后有一道疤
I had to wait until today cos he has a scar on the back of his neck
他头发长的时候看不见
and when his hair is long you can't see it.
他今天去理发…
疤不在了
- He went to have a haircut today...
- And the scar was gone.
不 疤还在！
No! It's still there!
当然还在那了 你说呢？他还是泰德
Of course it's still there.
What did you expect? He's still Ted.
抱歉 我能说句话吗？
别这样！他仍然是你丈夫
- Excuse me, can I say one thing?
- Please! He's still your husband Ted.
我知道一些事…
凯瑟琳？
- I know something...
- Katherine?
我能说句话吗？
凯瑟琳？
- Could I say one thing?
- Katherine!
稍等
Just a minute.
凯瑟琳
给我一分钟就好 行吗？
- Katherine.
- Just give me a minute, will you?
你相信我吗？
Will you trust me?
相信我好吗？行吗？
Will you please trust me? Will you?
我是公务员 这是一种爱国的表现
I work for the county.This is a public-spirited gesture.
我会告诉你我的名字……
金博纳想让人适应世界
- I will give you my name...
- Kibner wants people to fit the world.
我想要报告这个
我想要世界适应人
- I wanna report this.
- I want the world to fit people.
我们待会儿再说这些
荷马（诗人）哪儿去了？卡赞扎基斯（小说家）哪儿去了？
- We'll talk about this later.
- Where's Homer? Or Kazantzakis?
捷克伦敦（小说家）哪儿去了？
伊莎贝拉哪儿去了？
- Where's Jack London?
- Where's Elizabeth?
我害怕！
我理解 我知道
- I'm afraid!
- I understand, I know.
我理解 把手给我
I understand. Let me have your hand.
凯瑟琳 相信我
他多出色啊！
- Katherine, just trust me.
- Isn't he wonderful?
别这样
Come on.
那里 这样挺好的 不是吗？我后面是谁？
There. That's not so bad, is it?Who's this behind me?
是泰德
这就对了
- It's Ted.
- That's right.
坚强点 就这样 坚强点
Hold on. Come on, just hold on.
坚强点 放松点吧
Hold on. Just relax now.
你会没事的 感觉好些了吗？
是的 是的
- You gonna be all right? You feel better?
- Yeah. Yes.
你现在想回家了吗？
是的
- You wanna go home now?
- Yes.
你们明天能来找我聊聊吗？
拜托了… 明天
- Will you come and see me tomorrow?
- Please... tomorrow.
我们把话说透 好吗 我们三个？
Tomorrow we'll all talk. OK? The three of us?
好的 但是我现在最好送她回家了
OK, but I better take her home.
当然 没问题
Yes. It's OK.
明天见
好的
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- OK.
好吗？
好的
- All right?
- OK.
谢谢
Thank you.
他们对事故不感兴趣
They don't wanna hear about the accident.
这是个大阴谋
It's a big conspiracy.
什么是阴谋？
所有事
- What's a conspiracy?
- Everything.
让一下
Excuse me.
我知道你想说什么
I understand what you're trying to say.
我是公共卫生署的伊丽莎白・德里斯科尔 电话联系
My name is Elizabeth Driscoll,the Public Health Department. Call me.
凯瑟琳！走吧 凯瑟琳
Katherine! Come on, Katherine.
那个女人的丈夫不再是他本人了
That woman's husband is not her husband.
我看到过他跟杰弗里在一起 他是他们中的一员 她知道了
I saw him with Geoffrey. He's one of them. She knows about it
没人要帮她
不是这样的 有人帮她（医生接的话）
- and nobody's helping her.
-That's not ture No. Somebody's helping her.
我很高兴你听到了 戴维・金博纳会帮她的（英文字幕不太对）
I'm glad you heard that. David, Elizabeth.
我都听了一个星期了 现在都流行起来了
I've heard it all week. It's popular.
什么意思 什么流行起来了？
我刚才想要告诉你
- What's that. what's getting popular?
- I was trying to tell you
我也知道有些人……
有些人变了
- that I also know somebody...
- Who's changed.
是的
我们去外边谈吧
- Yes.
- Can we go outside and talk about it?
上面有一位女士 红头发蓝裙子的 她对你的作品很感兴趣
Listen, there's a lady up top - red hair,
blue dress. She's interested in your work.
我这个星期已经从六位病人哪里听过这个该死的故事了
I've heard the same damn story this week from six patients.
人们正在改变 变得没有人性了
People are changing,becoming less human.
这正发生在我们周围
It's happening all around us.
这不是我们要说的
That's not what we're talking about.
这跟与我生活的人没有关系
This has nothing to do with the man I live with.
这当然有关系了 你没看见吗？
It has everything to do with it. Don't you see?
人们聚散匆匆 因为他们不想负责任
People step in and out of relationships
because they don't want responsibility.
所以婚姻都见鬼去了 家庭也支离破碎
That's why marriages are going to hell.
The family unit is shot to hell.
戴维 你没认真听她说
别插嘴！
- David, you're not listening to her.
- Stay out of this!
你看 这就是问题所在
You see, that's the point.
我正听着呢 但是他觉得我没有听 为什么？
I'm listening,but he doesn't think I am. Why?
因为他不认为我会认真对待
Because he doesn't expect me to bother enough, or to care.
伯利克 最后说一遍 停下！
停下什么？！
- Bellicec, for the last time, stop!
- Stop what?!
站住了 安静点 闭嘴
杰克！
- Stand still, be quiet, and shut up!
- Jack!
看了我刚才做的事你有什么感想？
How did you feel about what I just did?
为什么要进商店？他疯了
Why in the store? He's a nut.
你有什么感觉？
How did you feel?
你大概吓到了
You were probably shocked.
你想把你的感官封闭起来
You wanted to shut your feelings off,
或者骗自己什么都没发生 因为这样你就不用面对了
maybe make believe it wasn't happening
cos then you don't have to deal with it.
我想要帮助书店里那个可怜的女人
I wanna deal with that poor woman in the bookstore.
为什么
Why?
你跟她有同感吗？
Do you identify with her?
是的
Yes.
好的
OK.
来吧
Come on.
假如我告诉过你 凯瑟琳正想疏离这段关系
Suppose I were to tell you that Katherine
is trying to escape from a relationship.
他正在对她进行治疗
那他就能把我朝墙上推吗？
- He's treating her.
- So why'd he push me against a wall?
她很不安
她看起来不错
- She's upset.
- She looks fine.
她很不安 杰克
我现在看你倒是挺不安的
- She is upset, Jack.
- You look upset to me now.
帮我个忙 行吗？
当然 什么都行
回家去 一会我会给你打电话
Do me a favour, will ya?
Go home and I'll call you later.
回家 让我们单独呆一会
回家？
- Go home and leave us alone for a bit.
- Go home?
行吗？
好的 好的
- OK?
- OK. OK.
谢谢
Thank you.
你正在钻牛角尖
You're jumping to a bizarre conclusion.
你的家人正在变成其他人？
That this man you live with
has been replaced by somebody else.
这听起来更像是你骗自己相信他变了
Isn't it more likely you want to believe he's changed
因为你想要找个借口摆脱他
because you're really looking for an excuse to get out?
我不知道
I don't know.
你能在斟酌一下吗？
Will you think about it, please,
在你要采取什么行动之前？
before you make a move?
在你跳出来并毁掉你所拥有的一切之前 再想想好吗？
Before you jump and destroy something you have. Will you?
好吗？
Please?
好的
Yeah.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我只是在心里上给她贴了一块创可贴 马修
I just gave her a psychological Band-Aid, Matthew.
我应该再多说几句的
I should talk to her some more.
你可以带她来我办公室 明天下午四点左右
You could bring her by my office tomorrow around four.
他到底怎么了？
What's the matter with her?
像是有一种导致幻想的流感正在爆发
It's like there's some kind of hallucinatory flu going around.
人们在一两天之内就会克服 我能做的就是对症下药
People get over it in a day or two. All I can do is treat the symptoms.
她会没事吗？
She's gonna be OK?
睡一宿好觉绝对没有坏处
A good night's sleep wouldn't hurt.
这会传染吗？
哦 马修！
- Is it contagious?
- Oh, Matthew!
把她带回到她男朋友那（大夫想歪了）
你误会了
- Take her home to her boyfriend.
- That wasn't what I was thinking.
我刚才是在想 卫生署有没有必要介入调查
I was just wondering if the Health Department should look at it.
我不知道谁能给出答案
Who knows? I don't know.
我倒是想给出答案
I wish I did.
好吧
OK.
带她回家 马修
Take her home, Matthew.
啊 杰克 读书会怎么样？
Ah, Jack. How was the book party?
那是金博纳的新书吗？
Is that Kibner's new book?
没朗诵你的诗吗？
Didn't get to read your poetry?
对不起 杰克
I'm sorry, Jack.
晚安 这里是伯利克浴室
Good evening. Bellicec Baths.
是的 我们建议在卡利斯托加火山灰泥浆中浸泡15分钟
Yes, we recommend the 1 5-minute soak
in Calistoga volcanic ash,
水波漩涡浴就是这样的
that's followed by an Aqua-Surge whirlpool dip.
嗨 能帮我出来吗？
Hey, can you help me outta here?
伯利克！
Bellicec!
我跟你说话的 帮把手
I'm talking to you. Give me a hand.
帮我出来
Help me outta this thing.
斯坦…
Stan...
每周都有你这样的
Every week we go through this.
为什么你不能配合一下呢？
给我条毛巾
- Why can't you be more cooperative?
- Get me a towel.
你这样会受伤的
You are really gonna get hurt one of these days.
再给我一条毛巾 好吗？
Give me another towel, would you?
别这样
Come on.
南茜 把音乐关了
Nancy, shut the music off.
这是给花放的音乐 斯坦
It's for the plants, Stan.
去他的花 我讨厌音乐
Screw the plants. I hate the music.
这对我的花很有好处 她们喜欢
It's wonderful for my plants.They just love it.
花也有七情六欲的 知道吗 像人一样
Plants have feelings, you know,just like people.
这太神了 这种音乐会刺激植物的生长
It's fascinating. This type of music
stimulates the growth of the plants.
这已经被大量实验所证明
They've done tons of experiments on it.
拜托了 南茜 把音乐关掉
别紧张
- Come on, Nancy. Turn the music off.
- Relax.
太紧张可没法欣赏音乐
You're not gonna enjoy this if you don't.
哦！詹尼先生 你在这儿干什么？
Oh! Mr Gianni, what are you doing here?
伯利克太太 一定要读一下
This is must reading, Mrs Bellicec.
维利科夫斯基的《冲突中的世界》
Worlds ln Collision by Velikovsky.
哦 当然 我看过很多遍了 你看过《造星人》吗？
Oh, yes. I've read that many times. Have you read Star Maker
奥拉夫.斯特普尔顿写的 那个也值得一读
by Olaf Stapledon? That's must reading, too.
好了 实在太晚了 詹尼先生
你真是才女
- Well, it's awfully late, Mr Gianni.
- You're so smart.
哦 詹尼先生 你在泥浆里坐得太久了
Oh, Mr Gianni, you've been sitting in that mud too long.
说不定有点过头了 知道吗
It is possible to overdo it, you know.
哦 对了 谢谢你上次送我的那盆花
Oh, by the way, thank you for that plant
you gave me last time.
我送你进去
I'll walk you inside.
没有必要
You don't have to.
杰弗里？
Geoffrey?
他真体贴
That was sweet of him.
你还好吗？
You all right?
明早见
I'll see you tomorrow morning.
谢谢 马修 你让我感觉好多了
Thank you, Matthew. You've really made me feel better.
我会考虑金博纳的话的
And I'm gonna think about what Kibner said.
好吧
OK.
谢谢你 晚安
Thanks for helping. Goodnight.
再见
See you.
杰克？
Jack?
宝贝 你在哪？
Honey, where are ya?
我不想打断你思考 但是我想去吃中国菜
I don't wanna disturb you if you're
thinking, but I could do with some chinese food.
我一天没吃饭了 哦…
I haven't eaten all day. Oh...
哦 杰克 这样会喘不上气的
Oh, Jack, you're gonna suffocate.
我的鼻子…
My nose...
让我离开！让我离开！
Let me out! Let me out!
我鼻子出血了
My nose is bleeding.
谁呀？
Who is it?
是马修
It's Matthew.
进来吧
怎么了？
- Come on in.
- What happened?
在后边
Back here.
我是把你当朋友才叫你来的
哦 杰克…
- Matthew, I called you here as a friend.
- Oh, Jack...
你是不是负责上报传染病或者有关尸体的事？
Do you report things like contagious
disease or a body in a place of business?
杰克 让他看看吧
你发现了尸体吗？
- Let him look at it.
- You found a body?
没有 没什么要紧的
我还以为是杰克呢
- No, not necessarily.
- I thought it was Jack.
是他吗？
Is that him?
是的 单子下面就是
Yeah, under there.
开什么玩笑？
不是玩笑
- What kind of joke is this?
- It's no joke.
这是什么？
What is it?
这他妈到底是什么？！
别冲动 南茜
- What the hell is it?!
- Just keep calm, Nancy.
会传染吗？
Is it contagious?
你的客人看到过吗？
没有
- Did any of your customers see this?
- No.
被人看到我们就完了
It'd ruin us.
我去报警
别这样
- I'm calling the police.
- Don't do that.
为什么？
南茜 别
- Why?
- Nancy, don't.
因为我想杰克是对的
Because I think Jack is right.
这绝不是未成熟个体
It's not immature exactly.
他有张成年人的脸
He's got an adult face.
这是个妖怪 全身都是毛
这不一定
- It's a monster. It's got hair all over it.
- It's vague.
鼻子 嘴唇 头发
Nose, lips, hair.
双手 应有尽有 只是还不完善 没有人格 还没成型
Hands, everything,but no detail, no character. It's unformed.
杰克 别碰  你不知道这是什么
Jack, don't touch it. You don't know where it's been.
没有呼吸
No respiration.
也没有指纹
It's got no fingerprints.
没指纹吗？
No fingerprints?
像个胎儿
Like a foetus.
你刚说过这是成年人
You just said it was an adult.
我说是成年人是因为它很高
I said it was an adult because it was tall.
你多高 杰克？
六英尺四英寸
- How tall are you, Jack?
- Six foot four.
你有多重？
170磅
- How much do you weigh?
- 170.
问这些干什么？
哦 不要
- Why?
- Oh, no.
不要 马修
No, Matthew.
哦 杰克！
Oh, Jack!
你给谁打电话？
伊丽莎白
- Who are you calling?
- Elizabeth.
为什么？
Why?
为什么打给伊丽莎白？
Why are you calling Elizabeth?
马修…
为什么？
- Matthew...
- Why?
喂？
Hello?
伊丽莎白吗？能听见吗？我是马修 伊丽莎白 喂
Elizabeth? Can you hear me? It's Matthew, Elizabeth. Hello?
怎么了？
What's the matter?
伊丽莎白 能听见吗？
Elizabeth, can you hear me?
你是谁？
Who is this?
喂？
Hello?
你去哪儿？
我朋友有麻烦了
- Where are you going?
- A friend of mine is in trouble.
我们该怎么办？
给戴维・金博纳打电话
- What are we to do?
- Phone David Kibner.
让他马上来这儿见我 他的号码
Ask him to meet me here right away. There's his number.
怎么了？
我累了
- What's the matter?
- I'm tired.
起来
Stand up.
站起来！ 四下走走
宝贝儿 我口渴 我渴死了
- Stand up! Now walk around!
- Honey, I'm dry! I'm very dry.
我给你拿点水来 别睡着
I'll get you a drink. Just don't fall asleep.
来 宝贝儿
谢谢 宝贝儿
- Here, sweetie.
- Thanks, sweetie.
金博纳大夫马上就来
Dr Kibner will be here soon.
我要躺下好好想想 宝贝儿
I'm gonna lie down and think, honey.
我就是想点事
I'm just gonna think.
杰克 别睡！ 眼睛！
Jack, wake up! lts eyes!
哦 杰克 它睁眼了
Oh, Jack. It opened its eyes.
看见了吗？
See?
亲爱的？
Hon?
醒醒
Wake up.
醒醒！
Wake up!
我在这儿连个尸体的毛都没看着
I can't find anything in here that looks like a body.
没有尸体？
你说什么！
- No body?
- What!
你查看过最后…
我都找遍了
- Did you check the last...
- I looked everywhere.
嘿！你…… 嘿！
Hey! Did you... Hey!
你查看过左手边最后一个隔间了？
那根本没有尸体
- Did you check the last booth on the left?
- There's no body there.
应该在那儿啊！
It's got to be in here!
它有脉搏、心跳吗?
它睁眼了
- Did it have a pulse, a heartbeat?
- It opened its eyes.
你真的看见了吗？
我看到它鼻子出血了
- You actually saw that?
- I saw its nose bleed.
他的白毛还碰到了我的手
It had white hair, that touched my hand.
那儿有东西
There's something in here.
有一次南茜的一位老年顾客死在这儿 他心脏病发作沉下去了
Nancy lost an old guy in here once.
He had a heart attack and sank.
面对现实吧 伯利克
Face it, Bellicec.
只是你的朋友跟你搞恶作剧而已
You've got some friends who enjoy practical jokes.
我没有朋友 金博纳博士
I don't have any friends, Dr Kibner.
那就是你的敌人
Then some enemies.
看那儿
Look.
谁打开的？
Who opened this up?
等等 等等 谁呀？
Wait a second, wait a second. Who is it?
马修 尸体消失了
有人弄走了尸体
- Matthew, the body's gone.
- Somebody's took it.
不 你没看到吗？
这儿没什么可看的
- No. Did you see it?
- There was nothing here to see.
你想吵醒谁 马修？
Who are you waking up now, Matthew?
警察吗？我发现一具尸体
Police? I would like to report a body.
赶快把她带到我那里去
Take her to my place fast.
在我们回来前别让任何人进来
Don't let anybody in until we get back there.
上尉 他们报告说发现一具尸体
Lieutenant, these fellas reported the body.
你们都看到了吗？
不 只有我看到 马修・贝纳尔
- You both saw it?
- No, I'm the only one. Matthew Bennell.
贝纳尔先生 带我去看看现场吧
就在上面
- Mr Bennell, show me where you saw it.
- It's right up here.
伊丽莎白在哪儿？
Where's Elizabeth?
在哪儿？
在那儿
- Where?
- There.
那是伊丽莎白的替身
哪里？
- It's Elizabeth's double.
- Where?
只是一堆树叶和一个壶
Lots of leaves and a pot.
原本在这的 戴维 我对天发誓
It was there, David. I swear to God it was there!
警官 那是伊丽莎白的复制品
Officer, there was a duplicate of Elizabeth Driscoll,
它被弄走了
那个失踪的女人吗？
- and it's been taken.
- The missing woman?
她没失踪
那她在哪?
- She's not missing.
- Where is she?
她在马修那儿
别说出来
- She's at Matthew's.
- Don't tell him that!
那就是说没有什么失踪的尸体了
当然
- Then there is no missing body.
- That's right.
有的 被他弄走了！
不 他带走了伊丽莎白
- There is and he's taken it!
- No, he took Elizabeth.
你带走了伊丽莎白？
是的！
- You took Elizabeth away?
- Yes!
你破门而入
我必须这样 她在这不安全
- You broke in here.
- I had to because she was not safe here.
这么说你把她从这带走了
So you took her out of here.
不！我把她从这儿带走 她的另一个身体还在这儿
No! I took her from there. Her other body was in here...
别说了 马修 够了 别说了
Please stop. Matthew, that's enough! Please stop!
上尉 我是戴维・金博纳博士
哦 那个精神病专家
- Lieutenant, I'm Dr David Kibner.
- Ah, the psychiatrist.
我妻子看过你的书 她受益良多
My wife reads your books.
我很荣幸 这听着可能有点复杂
戴维……
- I'm glad. It sounds complicated,...
- David...
…但是我的朋友最近被他的感情所困扰
..but my friend has had some difficult
emotional experiences recently.
但是我想我们自己私下能处理
But I think this is something
we can work out amongst ourselves.
好的 那我就不管了
感激不尽
- All right, I'll leave this part of it with you.
- I appreciate it.
你不能再在这纠缠下去了 我们出去说
You can't accomplish anything here. We gotta get outside.
我想你可能会考虑起诉贝纳尔非法入侵
I think you might wanna consider filing
an unlawful entry against Mr Bennell.
我知道你要说什么 但是外面……
I know what you're saying, but outside...
不 我相信金博纳教授说的 伊丽莎白没事
No, I'll take Dr Kibner's word that Elizabeth is all right.
好吧 我们走吧
好的
- Fine, then let's go.
- OK.
伊丽莎白会回家吗？
Will Elizabeth be coming home?
不
No.
我得给她带几件衣服
I have to pick up some of her clothes.
好吧
All right.
好吧 我们退回去再回想一次
All right, let's back up
and go through it once more,
慢慢来
step by step.
你们都觉得在浴室里看到了尸体
You all thought you saw a body at the baths.
你们想它可能已经死了 你们不知道它是什么
You thought it was dead. You didn't know what it was.
你们都接触过它了 所有人
You touched it. All of you touched it.
南茜 你看到它睁开眼睛
它正好盯着我看
- Nancy, you saw it open its eyes.
- It looked right at me.
伯利克你也看到它睁眼了
不 我看到它鼻子出血
- And, Bellicec, you saw its eyes open.
- No, I saw its nose bleed.
如果你看到它鼻子出血 南茜看到他睁开眼睛
If you saw its nose bleed, and Nancy saw its eyes open,
那它一定活着
he must have been alive.
不 戴维 你是按照人的标准来判断的 但是它不是人
No, David. You're looking at it
as if it was human. It was not human.
马修 那它还能是什么？
不管是什么 绝对不是人
- Matthew, what else would it be?
- It was something, but not human.
他身上有白毛
它一直在生长
- It had white hair on it.
- It was growing.
杰克家里的那个像…
The one at Jack's was...
像杰克 但是没有伊丽莎白家的那个成熟
It was like Jack, but not as developed
as the one at Elizabeth's place.
它还有卷胡子
It had tendrils on it.
她家那个是复制她
The one at her place was duplicating her.
如果马修没有把我带走
If Matthew hadn't taken me away,
发生在杰弗里身上的事  就会在我身上重演
the same thing that's happened
to Geoffrey would have happened to me.
伊丽莎白 能跟我说说 在你印象中 到底发生了什么吗？
Elizabeth, would you please tell me, in
your opinion, exactly what is happening?
大家都被复制了
People are being duplicated.
一旦你被复制 你就变成它的一部分
And once it's happened to you, you're part of this thing.
这差点就发生在我身上！
It almost happened to me!
听着
Look,
你不相信伊丽莎白  是因为尸体消失了
the reason you don't believe Elizabeth
is because the other body disappeared.
因为被杰弗里弄走了
It disappeared because Geoffrey took it.
好吧 那我的替身都怎么样了？
Well, then what happened to my other body, then?
哦 伙计 能听听自己在说什么吗？
Oh, people, will you please listen to yourselves?
你们能听听自己在说什么吗？
Will you listen to what you are saying?
我能想象一具尸体被转移  甚至是尸体站起来自己离开
I can deal with a body being moved and
even with a body getting up and leaving,
但是当你说他的另一个身体
她的另一个身体 被复制…
but when you start talking about his other
body,her other body, being duplicated...
知道这到底有多荒谬吗？
Listen to how that sounds.
我们知道这听起来有多疯狂！但是你觉得我们现在在干什么？
We know how insane this sounds!
But what do you think we're doing?
你觉得我们编造了一切吗？
Do you think we're making it up?
你到底是哪里听不懂
你相信我的替身看起来像我 她的替身看起来象她吗？
Do you believe that my body looked like
me and that her body looked like her?
你觉得我们疯了吗？
D'you think we're crazy?
你为什么想说服我们  这只是我们想象出来的？
You are trying to make us believe
that we are seeing things. Why?
我只是想要帮忙
All I'm trying to do is help.
你半夜打电话给我 找我帮忙 我就是来帮忙的
You call me in the middle of the night and
ask me to help. That's all I'm trying to do.
好吧 如果我们吵醒了你 那么对不起
Well, I'm sorry if we woke you up!
如果我们打搅你了 那我们很抱歉
If we inconvenienced you, I guess we owe you an apology.
我是说… 我想这么做很不好！
I mean, I mean... I guess that's a rotten thing to do!
但是你也把我太太搅得心神不宁
You've upset my wife, too.
戴维 我不知道它是什么 或者它从哪来
David, I don't know what it is or where it comes from,
但是我看到了  而且我要给它点颜色
but I saw it and I'm gonna fight it.
马修 老伙计 我相信你
Matthew, my friend,... I believe you.
我们认识这么久 让我怎么能不相信你呢
I've known you too long not to believe you.
你想怎么做？
What do you wanna do?
如果我能得到官方的支持 我得启动应急预案
Well, if I could get official support,
I'd institute the emergency procedures
就是我们针对疟疾和军团热所制定的预案
that we use for cholera or legionnaires' disease.
你想要我做什么？
我想我能搞定健康署
- What do you want me to do?
- I can handle the Health Department.
但是如果引起恐慌  我们需要警察和保安
But if panic breaks out, we'll need the police and the Guard,
就是说市长
and that means the Mayor and...
市长在你那看病 是吗？
The Mayor's a patient of yours, isn't he?
你怎么知道的？
How did you know that?
你想要我做什么？
What do you want me to do?
你能说服他接我的电话吗？
Would you ask him to accept my telephone call?
我会在一个小时内给他打电话 我在办公室
I'll call him in a hour. I'll be at my office.
如果你有其他主意 随时跟我联系
If you have any other ideas, get in touch.
我等你电话
Call me.
谢谢
Thank you.
速战速决
The sooner the better.
真好闻
This smells lovely.
我想要你听我说
我听着呢 南茜
- I want you to listen to me.
- I am listening to you, Nancy.
我没有看错  我知道我看见的是什么
I am not seeing things. I know I saw what I saw
我也知道那东西正变成你  杰克  现在我们发现的尸体…
and I know it was turning into you, Jack.
Now, that body we found...
这花是从哪摘的？
That flower. Where did you get that?
花瓶里
是夹在花中间吗
- In the vase with the others.
- Just stuck in there?
是 怎么了？
杰弗里昨晚也给了我一支这样的
- Yeah. Why?
- Geoffrey gave me one last night.
那又怎样
So what?
是一个顾客  詹尼先生带过来的花
A customer, Mr Gianni, brought one of those to the baths.
然后呢？
So what?
快放下 杰克
只是一个豆荚开的花而已
- Put it down, Jack.
- It's a pod with a flower on it.
我在任何书里都查不到这种花
杰克 快放下
- I could not find that flower in any book.
- Jack, put it down.
只是一朵花而已 亲爱的
可能会有毒
- It's a pink flower, honey.
- It could be toxic.
四处都有这种花  像寄生虫一样长在其他植物上
I have seen these flowers all over.
They grow like parasites on other plants.
它们从哪来？
外太空
- Where are they coming from?
- Outer space.
它们不是从外太空来的
为什么不是？
- They're not from outer space.
- Why not?
它们就是不是
为什么？！
- They're not.
- Why?!
你胡说什么？太空花？
What are you talking about? A space flower?
为什么不是太空花？谁规定外星人一定会做金属战舰？
Why not a space flower? Why do we always expect metal ships?
我从来没提起过金属战舰
I've never expected metal ships.
它们一定是从其他途径进入我们的系统
There must be other ways they get in our systems.
对 它们可能通过接触或者香味  来进入我们的身体
Right. They could be getting into us through touch or fragrance.
到处都是麻烦 我们甚至还没来得及注意它们
We would never even notice it,
not from the impurities we have.
我是说 我们吃的东西呼吸的空气都是垃圾
I mean, we eat junk and we breathe junk.
我不知道它们从哪来 但是我感觉像是我被下毒了
I don't know where they're coming from,
but I feel as though I've been poisoned.
我们要把这些花带回实验室化验
We've gotta take those flowers in and have them analysed.
现在有一些东西
能进入我们的身体
- There's something here.
- They could get into us
然后打乱我们的遗传基因 再重新组合 改变我们
and screw up our genes like DNA, recombine us, change us.
哦 就是这样！
Oh, of course!
跟几年前着陆的那些火箭一样
This is the same way those rockets landed thousands years ago,
这样这些太空人就能通过跟猴子交配来创造人类
so those spacemen could mate with
monkeys and create the human race.
现在就是这样！
It's happening now!
你找谁？
戴维・金博纳
- Who do you wish to speak to?
- David Kibner.
他不在 下午才会回来
He's not in right now. He'll be back this afternoon.
能给他留言吗？我是马修・贝纳尔
Could you leave a message for him?
Matthew Bennell. B-E-N-N-E-L-L.
你电话是多少？
不用 他知道我电话
- And your number, please?
- No, he's got my number. Thank you.
我是詹姆斯・卓拉 副检察长 什么事？
James Grala, Deputy City Attorney. Can I help you?
我是马修・贝纳尔
My name is Matthew Bennell.
我是公共卫生署的代理调查员
B-E-N-N-E-L-L. I'm a deputy public health inspector.
你也要报告“冒充者”的事吗？
是的
- Is this another call about impostors?
- Yes.
你还跟别的部门说过吗？
没有
- We're the first agency you called?
- Yes.
很好 听着 贝纳尔先生 我们不想引起恐慌
Good. Listen, Mr Bennell, we don't wanna create a panic.
这边没人知道
No-one here knows.
我想让你暂时先呆在你的电话旁
I'd like you to stay by yourphone for a while.
我这就找人给你回电话 记下你说知道的一切
I'll have somebody call you back
and take down all you know.
好的 谢谢你
All right, thank you.
实验室够忙的了 伊丽莎白 我们不化验花
This is a busy lab, Elizabeth. We don't test flowers.
那是农业部的事
我知道
- They go to the Depart of Agriculture.
- I know where they go!
我想这应该是我们的责任 我想这个会影响到人
I think this is our problem. I think it is affecting people.
怎么影响？
How?
听着 艾伦 我已经说过了 我自己化验
Look, Allen, I have already said that I'll do all the testing.
你不用伸一跟手指  好吗？
You don't have to lift a finger. Can l?
你总是迟到 伊丽莎白 你的工作已经落下不少了
You've been consistently late, Elizabeth, and you're behind in your work,
所以 还是我来帮你化验吧
so I'll do the tests for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
给我48小时
艾伦 只有24小时
- It'll take 48 hours.
- Allen, 24.
我不明白你为什么要对这朵小小的花大动干戈
I can't understand why you've become so emotional about a little flower.
你好
Hello.
贝纳尔先生吗？
是的
- Mr Bennell?
- Yes.
健康署的？
是的
- From the Health Department?
- Yes.
我是泰德・杰索普 市长特别助理
嗯
- It's Ted Jessop, the Mayor's special assistant.
- Yes.
你遇到了奇怪的事？
是
- You've come across something strange?
- Yes.
我们最好在联合广场面谈
I'd like to suggest we meet in Union Square.
我们不能在电话里讲
这就去
- We can't talk over the phone.
- Right away.
那么 明天你还会跟我在这里碰头吗？贝纳尔先生
So you'll meet me here again tomorrow,Mr Bennell?
好的
Yeah.
不要跟别人讲 保密
Don't say a word to anyone. Keep it quiet.
听你的
Whatever you say.
请投15美分
接线员 我已经投了25美分了
- Please deposit 15 cents.
- Operator, I put in a quarter...
我是朱迪・汉克耳  市长特别助理
This is Judy Hinkell, the Mayor's special assistant.
你好 我是马修・贝纳尔
Yes. My name is Matthew Bennell.
市长正在开会
The Mayor's in conference,
但是金博纳博士给他打电话说了一些他的担心
but Dr Kibner called him personally to express his concern.
贝纳尔先生
And, Mr Bennell,
我们想听听你的意见  因为情况好像正在好转
we're asking for your discretion
because this thing might be abating.
喂？
Hello?
马修・贝纳尔？
是我
- Matthew Bennell?
- Yes.
我是联邦战备局的迈克尔
I'm Michaels, from the Federal Preparedness Agency.
这些关于奇怪的、无法解释的、病态尸体的报告
These reports of strange, unexplained, diseased bodies.
我想你还没有进行过化验
My understanding is you haven't analysed anything
你也没有任何组织样本
不 我……
- and you have no tissue samples.
- No, I'm...
贝纳尔先生 你的结论有点不着边 别钻牛角尖
Mr Bennell, it seems you'rejust winging
your conclusions. Keep an open mind.
我不是故意…
I had no intention...
别跟别人说这些复制身体的事
Don't mention to anyone about duplicate bodies.
我要处理…
抱歉 我要接一个电话
- I was gonna treat it...
- Excuse me, my otherphone is ringing.
什么事？
贝纳尔先生 严肃点
- Yes?
- This is serious business, Mr Bennell.
你是妄想狂吗？
不 不 不
- Is this just a case of paranoia?
- No, no, no.
你知道群体歇斯底里是什么样吗  贝纳尔先生？
Know what mass hysteria looks like, Mr Bennell?
我们不想引起恐慌
我们有优先权
- We don't want to create a panic.
- We have a primary authority.
谨慎点
Be cautious.
你的声音很痛苦
You sound distressed.
我想前途很光明  人们正在好转
- I think the horizon looks bright.
- People are returning to normal.
不  不  她没事了
No, no. She all right.
她现在好多了  好多了
She better now. Much better now.
是你丈夫让你来的吗？
不 不
- Did your husband ask you to come?
- No, no.
我想让大家都看到我已经恢复正常了
I want everybody to see that I'm back to myself again.
不 请稍等
No, wait. Please.
一会儿见  希望如此
I'll see you soon, I hope.
马修  这个频段什么都收不到
Matthew, I'm not getting a thing here.
哪去了？ 我什么新闻都收不到
Where is the... I'm not getting any news here.
不是应该有24小时滚动新闻吗？
Isn't there a 24-hour news?
我想如果去高处可能信号会好一些
I would think you'd have a good reception on the hill.
那有一辆维修车  用那个行吗？
There's a repair truck out here. Could that be to do with it?
她只是需要一些帮助睡觉的东西  明天她就完好如新了
She just needs something to help her
sleep. Tomorrow she'll be good as new.
我建议你也好好睡一觉  你已经竭尽所能了
I would suggest you get some sleep, too.
You've done everything you possibly can.
要我捎贝利斯一程吗？
Can I give the Bellicecs a ride?
不 我不回去
No, I'm not going back there.
我们睡汽车旅馆
你们可以呆在这儿
- We'll just get a motel.
- You can stay here.
谢谢
Thank you.
来吧
Come on.
我很感激你的帮助  戴维  谢谢你
I appreciate everything you've done, David. Thank you.
好好休息
一定  再见
- Get some sleep.
- Sure. See you.
马修  马修
Matthew. Matthew.
马修  它们正在蔓延  到处都是
Matthew, they're growing. They're everywhere!
叫醒大家！
Wake the others!
伊丽莎白  醒醒！它们从豆荚里长出来了
Elizabeth, wake up! They're growing out of these pods.
我去报警
伊丽莎白  醒醒
- I'll get the police.
- Elizabeth, wake up.
它们趁你睡觉就会抓住你  坐起来！
They get you when you sleep. Sit up!
伊丽莎白！伊丽莎白！醒了吗？
Elizabeth! Elizabeth, would you wake up?
你好  警察局
Hello. Police.
警官  我在后院发现四具尸体
Officer, I would like to report four bodies in my backyard.
你还好吗？
You OK?
等在那儿 贝纳尔先生
你怎么知道我的名字？
- Wait there, Mr Bennell.
- How do you know my name?
撂下电话  马修
Hang up, Matthew.
我没提我的名字！
撂下
- I didn't tell you my name!
- Hang up.
我没告诉他们我的名字！
他们已经是它的一部分了
- I didn't tell them my name!
- They're all a part of it.
它们都是豆荚里出来的  所有人都是
They're all pods, all of them.
你给谁打电话？
华盛顿
- Who are you calling?
- Washington.
中情局？联邦调查局？他们早就已经变成豆荚了
The CIA? The FBl? They're pods already.
我有朋友在司法部  我直接给他打
I've got a friend in the Justice Department.
I can dial direct.
你怎么跟他说？
哦  我的天！
- What are you gonna tell him?
- Oh, my God!
它们从豆荚里长出来了
They grow out of those pods!
它们切断了电源
They cut our power.
马修  它们封锁了街道
Matthew, they're barricading the street.
不！
No!
你想接哪里？
怎么是接线员？我是直接拨号的
- What number are you calling from?
- Operator? I was dialling direct.
我会帮你接通的  贝纳尔先生
I'll try the number, Mr Bennell.
它们上楼了  撂下电话  马修
- They're coming up here. Hang up, Matthew.
马修  有枪吗？
Matthew, do you have a gun?
没有
No.
我们怎么办？
从后门走
- What are we gonna do?
- Out the back door.
快点！杰克！
Hurry up! Jack!
那边走  楼梯下面  接着走  我会赶上你们的
That way. Under the stairs.
Go on. I'll catch up with you.
接着走  一直跑  别停下
Go on, keep on running! Don't stop!
继续跑！
Go on!
抓紧  跟着我
Quickly. Follow me.
我们走投无路了！
We're being cornered!
上帝啊！
Jesus!
趴下！
Get down!
马修  让他们呆在这儿  我去找帮手
Matthew, keep them here and I'll come back with help.
杰克
Jack.
杰克！
别 南茜
- Jack!
- No, Nancy.
不 杰克！杰克！
趴下
- No, Jack! Jack!
- Get down.
大爷在这儿呢  你们这群杂种！
Here I am, you pod bastard!
嘿  豆子们！
Hey, pods!
过来抓我呀  你们这群垃圾！
Come and get me, you scum!
码头检查完毕  收到
Wharf area is secure. Ten-four.
嫌犯正在逃跑  嫌犯正在逃跑
Suspects escaping. Suspects escaping.
哦耶  尽情发挥吧！
Oh, yeah, showtime!
是的先生  你算是来着了  我们这里有光溜溜的小妞
Yes, sir, you're walking the right way. We got nude girls...
只此一家别无分号
It's all going on right here.
都是活生生、光溜溜的 先生 保证大饱眼福
It's all live, it's all naked, sir. Guaranteed action here.
一定让你如获新生
Guaranteed to make you feel like a new man.
别错过！  快回来！
Come on back here! Come on back here!
听到了吗？别错过！快回来！这就是你要的
D'you hear me? Come on back here! This is it.
里面有你的小情人儿  有男也有女
We got male and female love back here...
去哪儿？
去机场
- Where to?
- The airport.
610向南去机场
6-10 proceeding south to airport,
搭载2名乘客  H类型
carrying two passengers, type H.
重复  H类型
610收到
- Repeat. Type H.
- 6-10, confirmed.
晚上真不错
Some night, eh?
是啊
- Yeah.
你们要去哪儿？
Where are you heading?
我说过了  去机场
I said. The airport.
不  我是问哪班飞机
No. I mean which airline.
联合航空的
- United.
你们要出城公干？
You got business outta town?
不  我们不出城  我们接一个从波士顿来的人
No, we're not leaving. We're meeting
someone coming in from Boston.
怎么回事？
What is it?
这是怎么了？
What's going on?
哦 没事
Oh, nothing.
两个都是
Both of 'em.
哈利  狗狗  快醒醒！
快看  有一个豆荚
- Harry, pooch, wake up!
- Look, there's a pod.
所有有家人在伯克利、奥克兰和伊丽莎白的
All those with families in Berkeley, Oakland and Elizabeth.
第七部队  特别援助
Unit Seven, special assistance.
你们能去健康署吗？
Could we have you over by the Health Department?
红色城市  所有有家人在红色城市的人
Red city, please. All with red city families.
看看它们！ 明火执仗的
Look at them! Right out in the open.
它们就是这么干的
That's how they do it.
他们就是这么传播的  这些人全都变了
That's how they spread it.All those people are changed.
第七部队  特别援助
Unit Seven, special assistance.
你们能立刻去健康署吗？
Could we have you over by the Health Department immediately?
马修  我们不可能阻止他们了！
Matthew, we'll never be able to stop them!
不 我们能阻止
Yes, we will.
我们不行！看看外面 它们控制了整个城市
We can't! Look it, they control the whole city.
我们无论如何会有办法的
We'll find a way somehow.
哦 马修 我撑不下去了！
Oh, Matthew, I can't go on!
我想睡觉  我挺不住了
I wanna go to sleep. I can't stay awake any more.
你必须撑住
You have to.
你必须保持清醒
You have to stay awake.
还在车里的人能去果园街终点站报道吗？
Would somebody in transportation report to the Grove Street terminal?
是的 博卡多的药  他吃药像吃糖
或者他以前吃糖一样猛
Yup. Boccardo's pills. He eats these like candy... or he used to.
吃两片
Take some.
什么药？
斯必得  这能让我们保持清醒
- What are they?
- Speed. It'll keep us awake.
该吃几颗？
上面写着“吃一颗”
- How many are you supposed to take?
- It says "Take one".
吃五颗
Take five.
他们知道我们在这儿
They know we're here.
杰克  上帝啊！
Jack, my God!
不
No.
如果我们昨晚乖乖睡觉  那现在就会容易得多
Would have been a lot easier if we'd just gone to sleep last night.
戴维  不！
David, no!
哦  上帝啊！ 不！ 不！ 马修！
别碰她！
- Oh, my God! No! No! Matthew!
- Don't touch her!
戴维  别让它们碰她！  别让它们碰她
David, don't let them touch her! Don't let them touch her!
别让它们碰她
Don't let them touch her.
你们现在要干什么？
我们会离开这里！
- What are you gonna do?
- We'll leave the city!
求你了  杰弗里
戴维  让我们走吧
- Please, Geoffrey.
- David, let us go.
让我们离开这里！
你们没必要离开这里
- Let us leave the city!
- You don't have to leave the city.
什么都没变  你可以过以往的生活
Nothing changes. You can have the same life.
但是我们会怎么样？
But what happens to us?
你们会重生在一个无忧无虑的世界
You'll be born again into an untroubled world,
没有牵挂  没有恐惧…
free of anxiety, fear,...
等等
没有仇恨
- Wait.
- ..hate.
戴维我们会死的
不是这样  戴维是对的
- David, you're killing us.
- That's not true. David's right.
你的大脑和记忆都会完全吸收  一切都会完好无损的
Your minds and memories'll be totally
absorbed. Everything remains intact.
你这辈子都在跟他唱反调 你手里拿着什么?
You've never agreed with him in your life
before! What are you talking about?
你们…
What are you...
戴维 我们会死的
David, you're killing me.
这是药水是干什么的？
只是帮你睡眠的温和镇静剂
- What is this supposed to do?
- Just a mild sedative to help you sleep.
我恨你
我们不恨你
- I hate you.
- We don't hate you.
现在起再不需要恨…或者爱
There's no need for hate now... or love.
我爱你  马修
I love you, Matthew.
有人会站出来挑战你的
There are people who will fight you.
他们会阻止你
They'll stop you.
一个小时以内…你们就不会想让他们阻止我了
In an hour... you won't want them to.
别被老脑筋所束缚
Don't be trapped by old concepts.
你就要进化成为一种新的生命形式
You're evolving into a new life form.
过来看吧
Come and watch.
我们从一个濒死的世界来到这里
We came here from a dying world.
我们穿过宇宙  经过一个又一个行星
We drift through the universe from planet to planet,
被太阳帆推动着
pushed on by the solar winds.
我们适应了…并且生存下来
We adapt... and we survive.
生命的功能幸存下来
伊丽莎白！
- The function of life is survival.
- Elizabeth!
打开冷库  快点
Open the freezer, quick.
这扇门吗？
是的
- This door?
- Yup.
关上门
Shut the door.
我们怎么出去？
How are we gonna get outta here?
走大门  快点
Through the door. Come on.
那是什么？
What's that?
我找不到杰克
I've lost Jack.
我们跑散了
We got separated.
我不知道他在哪  我到处都找了  你们见过他吗？
I don't know where he is. I've looked
everywhere. Have you seen him?
南茜  这座楼被包围了  你是怎么进来的？
Nancy, this building is surrounded.
How did you get in?
我在它们中间晃荡几个小时了  他们很好糊弄
I've been wandering among 'em for hours. They can be fooled.
怎么做？
How?
别流露出感情  隐藏你的感情
Don't show any emotions. Hide your feelings.
睡觉时怎么办？
我们轮流守夜
- And when you sleep?
- We'll watch over each other.
好的
咱们去找杰克
- OK.
- Let's find Jack.
我们去修理它们  好吗？
We're going to beat them. OK?
好
OK.
嘿！去那边排队
Hey! The lines are over there.
XB-25. XB-25. 第五安置点 请讲
XB-25. XB-25. Station 5. Come in.
我是第五安置点  正按B计划行动  等待金博纳小队
Yes. Station 5. Proceeding
as per plan B. Awaiting Kibner unit.
第五安置点  请讲
Station 5. Come in.
XB-25 在健康署正门口  请指示
XB-25. In front of the Health Department.
Request instructions.
你正在去索萨利托的队伍  请向前走
You are in the right place for Sausalito.
Please keep moving right along.
只去索萨利托 请注意
Sausalito only, please.
如果有疑问就提出来
Ask if you have a question.
黄色区域是装卸区
The yellow zone is for loading and unloading only.
如果你要做其他事  不要进入黄色区域
If you have other business, stay clear of the yellow.
不要进入黄色区域  这里是装卸区
Stay clear of the yellow. That's for loading or unloading.
抓住他们！抓住他们！
Get them! Get them!
抓住他们！
Get them!
加把劲  起来
Come on, get up.
哦  天啊！
Oh, God!
你看到他们了？
You see them?
他们就是在这儿育苗的  在这里培育他们的种子
This is where they grow them.
This is where they cultivate them.
真大
It's enormous.
我们怎么办？这里有这么多
What are we gonna do? There are so many.
我们要想办法阻止他们
We've got to figure out a way of stopping them.
你能走吗？
Can you walk?
我试试
来  扶着我试着走起来
- I'll try.
- Here, hold on to me and try and walk.
哦 上帝！你没事吗？
Oh, God! Are you all right?
一个工厂…
A factory...
他们正在种植幼苗
They're growing them.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
我爱你
I love you.
我爱你！
I love you!
加把劲
Come on.
哦  不行  我不行！
Oh, I can't. I can't!
音乐
Music.
有船
Ships.
有船了…有船了！
Ships... Ships!
有船了！我们能逃出去了！
Ships! We can get away!
我下去看看  一会儿就回来  呆在这儿
I'll go down there. I'll be right back. Stay here.
呆在这儿
Stay here.
旧金山港湾
哦  上帝啊！
- ..San Francisco Bay area.
- Oh, God!
大部分集市都在星期六晚和星期天
Mostly fair Saturday night and Sunday.
未来会有降温趋势  能见度也会增加
There will be a cooling trend with improved visibility.
今天夜间最低气温10度  星期六4度
Night-time lows in the fifties tonight
and in the forties Saturday.
风向专为西南风  风速每小时10-20英里
Light winds becoming north-westerly, 10-20mph...
伊丽莎白  不！ 不！
Elizabeth, no! No!
醒醒 醒醒
Wake up. Wake up.
醒醒！
Wake up!
我爱你
I love you.
船就在那儿  伊丽莎白
The boat's there, Elizabeth.
船就在那儿
The boat's there.
我们能坐船离开了
It's gonna take us away.
没什么值得害怕的
There's nothing to be afraid of.
它们说得不错
They were right.
一点都不疼
It's painless.
感觉很好
It's good.
来吧
Come.
睡吧
Sleep.
他一定在这里的某个地方
He must be here somewhere.
我们走这边
Let's go this way.
他一定在附近某处
那边有一个 我想
- He must be around here somewhere.
- There's one over here, I think.
我们会抓住他的
- We'll get him.
他不能永远不睡觉
He can't stay awake for ever.
所有要接从杰克逊郡来的校车的的人
All those meeting incoming
school buses from Jackson County,
请到礼堂报名
please report to the auditorium.
进港航班时刻表已经贴到信息栏里
Schedule of incoming flights is posted by the information booth.
在贝尔福德、尤金、波特兰、西雅图、温哥华有亲属的人
All those with relatives in Bedford,
Eugene, Portland, Seattle, Vancouver,
请去市政厅报名
report to City Hall.
为什么我们现在就要午睡 芬利太太
Why do we have to take our nap now, Mrs Finley?
我不想睡觉  我还不累
I don't wanna take a nap. I'm not tired.
去往下列城市者请注意
Please pay attention to the following cities:
圣克鲁斯、圣巴巴拉、大洛杉矶区
Santa Cruz, Santa Barbara, the Greater Los Angeles area.
货车和客车将在3：25、4：25、5：25 发车
Trucks and buses will be leaving at 3.25, 4.25, 5.25.
第五区 公务员 代码七  重复  代码七
Sector 5, city employees, code seven. Repeat. Code seven.
请接机 包括以下航空公司的飞机
Meeting all incoming flights -
SFO, LAX, JFK,
SFO、LAX、 JFK、ORD、SAA、ETl...
ORD, SAA, ETl...
马修
悲剧了